## Brandon Franklin

Loxahatchee, Florida - 561.674.6225 - brandon.h.franklin@gmail.com

# **Objective:**

Curate robust web applications utilizing the latest technologies and adhering to the highest standards. Experienced with all stages of web development including design concept and prototyping, solutions, development, testing, QA, deployment, release, and maintenance. Strong background in design theory and effective communication between all teams involved in the software development lifecycle.

### **Education:**

Bachelor of Graphic Design, Digital Media Arts College(Lynn University), Boca Raton, FL

- Delta Epsilon Iota Honor Society

# **Work Experience:**

#### Penn Entertainment

Senior Front End Engineer, April 2022 - Present

- Collaborate, prioritize, estimate, plan, build, test, document, and maintain features for ESPNBet and theScore sportsbook web applications consumed by millions of users
- Participate in peer and mob code reviews to keep the team aligned and always learning from each other
- Create documentation for best practices to utilize when onboarding team members and future reference
- Contribute to a team that spearheaded the use of a monorepo containing a UI library, component library, design system, and more that is consumed by all of our apps to enforce a standard user experience
- Assist in the conceptualization and documentation of processes and procedures that the web team and engineering org use to hold each other accountable throughout the software development lifecycle
- Conduct interviews, provide feedback to hiring managers, and mentor new hires during the onboarding process including 30/60/90 day check-ins

### 7Summits, an IBM Company

Senior Front End Developer, October 2021 - April 2022

- Assist with the training and onboarding of new team members
- Mentor new team members on projects so they feel empowered when working alone on future projects
- Work with tech leads to define user story solution notes, estimations, acceptance criteria, documentation, and deployments
- Participate in quarterly projects with team members to improve development standards and define best practices for other engineers and members of the technology team

## Front End Developer, November 2019 - October 2021

- Utilize Salesforce and modern web development technologies to create solutions for our clients
- Build Aura/Lightning Web Components for Salesforce Lightning Experience and Communities
- Contribute to Product IP, including bolts and accelerators available in Salesforce AppExchange
- Work with the team to write, test, and troubleshoot Apex controllers/triggers
- Responsive design utilizing the Salesforce Lightning Design System
- Configuring Communities within the Lightning Community Builder
- Interfacing directly with clients in coordination with the project's Tech Lead
- Utilizing Jira software to work on projects using Agile methodology for project management
- Working with back-end developers to create solutions in tandem

## Brandon Franklin

Loxahatchee, Florida - 561.674.6225 - brandon.h.franklin@gmail.com

#### <u>Cendyn</u>

Lead Front End Developer, January 2019 - November 2019

- Conceptualize, prototype, and build product features that integrate with legacy and modern technologies
- Work with other team leaders to determine tech stacks for product development (Vue, .NET Core, SQL)
- Update and maintain product integrity through ongoing enhancements
- Conduct code reviews for internal and offshore teams
- Create and update documentation for best practices, component usage and API consumption using the latest features in JavaScript

Front End Developer, February 2016 - January 2019
Production Manager, May 2015 – February 2016
Product Services Manager, July 2013 – May 2015
Production Coordinator, July 2012 - July 2013
Web Production Specialist, July 2011 - July 2012

## **Projects:**

#### Sales Suite Product Redesign

- Responsible for leading a team of other departments through the ideation, iteration, validation, prototyping, and testing of concepts for the redesign of our flagship product.
- Directly influence tech stack and product design decisions for a maintainable and scalable environment.

#### **Living UI Kit**

- Worked with the UX Design team to cultivate a philosophy for rebranding the entire suite of 22 products. This involved conceptualization and prototyping items to include in the kit.
  - o Implementation & Testing
  - o "How to" tutorial
  - O Updates and maintenance of the code base

## Hilton Worldwide Product Suite

Responsible for the recruitment, training, and development of 4 new team members in an effort to
increase productivity by the end of the year. The team was able to exceed expectations two-fold and
deliver the final release of the project early and under budget.

## **Skills:**

#### **Proficiencies**

Vue, Vuex, React, Next, TypeScript, GraphQL, Zustand, Asynchronous Programming, Unit Testing, CI/CD(Github Workflows), Percy, Datadog, Bugsnag, Storybook, HTML5, CSS3, A11y, LESS/SASS Preprocessing, Bootstrap, Foundation, JavaScript, ES6, Material UI, Vuetify, Tailwind, Bulma, Version Control (TFS, GIT, SVN), Salesforce Administration/Development/Experience Cloud/Lightning Web Components, Responsive Web Design, Cross-Browser Compatibility, Adobe Creative Suite, VS Code, IntelliJ, Working with Offshore/Remote Teams

#### **Familiarizations**

Angular 1x, Nuxt, MVC, ASP.NET, .NET Core, API Creation, NX, Node, NPM, Yarn, Grunt, Gulp, Webpack, Browserify, Lean UX, DevOps, AutoRabit

### **Certifications**

Salesforce Certified Javascript Developer, Salesforce Certified Administrator, Salesforce Certified UX Designer

Define. Measure. Analyze. Implement. Control.